<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Development | Seth Hall]]></title>
  <link href="http://middle8media.github.com/blog/categories/development/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://middle8media.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-29T21:28:11-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://middle8media.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Seth Hall]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Adventures in Wi-Fi]]></title>
    <link href="http://middle8media.github.com/blog/2013/05/29/new-adventures-in-wi-fi/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-29T10:26:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://middle8media.github.com/blog/2013/05/29/new-adventures-in-wi-fi</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So this week I started a new adventure. I accepted a full time, remote position at <a href="http://ushahidi.com/">Ushahidi</a> as their Front-End Designer &amp; Developer. This week is my first week and so far, so good. I am working with an amazing global team that spans across 7 time zones. They are awesome people and have provided a very warm welcome. <!-- more --></p>

<h2>OK, but what does Ushahidi actually do?</h2>

<p><blockquote><p>"We're a non-profit tech company that specializes in developing free and open source software for information collection, visualization and interactive mapping."</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Unpacked, we build things: mostly software platforms, but sometimes <a href="http://brck.com/">hardware</a>, too.</p>

<p><img class="center" src="http://5d0851659fb2c02cd1ff-af1bbd52513c4a786d3ef25bdd02ad4c.r84.cf1.rackcdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/promo-brck-500x260.jpg" width="789" title="brck" alt="alt"></p>

<h2>What Else?</h2>

<p><blockquote><p>"We build tools for democratizing information, increasing transparency and lowering the barriers for individuals to share their stories."</p></blockquote></p>

<p><blockquote><p>"We're a disruptive organization that is willing to take risks in the pursuit of changing the traditional way that information flows."</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Unpacked: Ushahidi tends to try new, edgy things. We work in spaces where the idea is that we're disrupting some status quo organization or industry for the good of ordinary people (the crowd). This of course means that we're okay with people not at first getting what we do, or liking it.</p>

<h3>In other words ... my kind of place!!</h3>

<p>Needless to say I am very excited to be a part of such a visionary and global company. Thanks to the <a href="http://www.ushahidi.com/about-us/team">Ushahidi Team</a> for the opportunity to learn, grow and help make a difference.</p>

<p>Check us out <a href="http://ushahidi.com/">online</a> and follow us on <a href="https://twitter.com/ushahidi">Twitter</a> for product releases, news and updates.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[[Pro-Tip] Chrome Web Inspector - Dock to Right]]></title>
    <link href="http://middle8media.github.com/blog/2013/01/24/chrome-web-inspector-dock-to-right/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-24T13:46:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://middle8media.github.com/blog/2013/01/24/chrome-web-inspector-dock-to-right</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently saw a Paul Irish video where he had his Chrome Web Inspector docked on the right. In my development workflow Chrome Web Inspector was always docked on the bottom, but seeing it docked on the right just made more sense. So I decided to enable that feature, but I initially had trouble finding it. So I thought I would share how to find the "Dock to Right" feature for anyone else having this trouble.</p>

<p>Here you go...</p>

<pre><code>Right Click
Inspect Element  or ( ALT + CMD + i )
Find the dock icon at bottom left
Long click for "Dock to Right" option
Done
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tame the Wild]]></title>
    <link href="http://middle8media.github.com/blog/2013/01/19/tame-the-wild-with-statamic/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-19T22:14:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://middle8media.github.com/blog/2013/01/19/tame-the-wild-with-statamic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week I have been developing the web site/web app hybrid of our new independent film venture Indie Film Equities. IFE is the official funding portal for <a href="http://newriverreleasing.com">New River Releasing's</a> feature length films, a place where Independent Filmmakers and Investors meet. The site is built on WordPress using the <a href="https://www.e-junkie.com/ecom/gb.php?ii=606601&amp;c=ib&amp;aff=214644&amp;cl=64302">Standard Theme</a>, and is set to launch sometime this year <em>(we are waiting on specific guidelines from the SEC, but that is another blog post)</em>. As I was building out the membership login/payment functionality<!-- more -->, I was able to  seriously dive into PHP for the first time. PHP is the server-side language that makes up the heart and soul of WordPress and so far it is a lot of fun to work with.</p>

<p>Anyway, Wordpress has been and continues to be a great CMS for myself and my clients, but I have recently discovered a potential game changer for how I develop Content Management Systems, if not a complete game changer then at least a worthy option. I am referring to <a href="http://statamic.com/">Statamic</a>.</p>

<p><img src="/images/statamic.png"></p>

<p>Statamic is a dynamic, static site generator.  <code>static + dynamic = Statamic</code>. Pretty clever.</p>

<p>In the words of Statamic's creator <a href="http://jackmcdade.com/">Jack McDade</a></p>

<blockquote>Statamic is a dynamic, flat file content management system that’s completely powered by static files. That’s right, there’s no database in between your application and your content.</blockquote>


<p>That sounds pretty awesome to me. Bring it.</p>

<p>There are tons of resources and documentation on the <a href="http://statamic.com/">Statamic Home Page</a> and the developer community is already robust, which means this platform should be in active development for a while and the third party add-ons should cover a variety of needs. Also, at $29 for a Personal license and $99 for a Professional license, you get a lot of bang for your buck. Without a doubt, I will be buying this for my next project.</p>

<p>Has anyone used this platform? Is anyone developing Add-Ons?</p>

<p>Please share your thoughts and experience.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
