<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Film | Adventures in Wi-Fi]]></title>
  <link href="http://middle8media.github.com/blog/categories/film/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://middle8media.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-30T13:37:39-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://middle8media.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Seth Hall]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tame the Wild]]></title>
    <link href="http://middle8media.github.com/blog/2013/01/19/tame-the-wild-with-statamic/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-19T22:14:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://middle8media.github.com/blog/2013/01/19/tame-the-wild-with-statamic</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week I have been developing the web site/web app hybrid of our new independent film venture Indie Film Equities. IFE is the official funding portal for <a href="http://newriverreleasing.com">New River Releasing's</a> feature length films, a place where Independent Filmmakers and Investors meet. The site is built on WordPress using the <a href="https://www.e-junkie.com/ecom/gb.php?ii=606601&amp;c=ib&amp;aff=214644&amp;cl=64302">Standard Theme</a>, and is set to launch sometime this year <em>(we are waiting on specific guidelines from the SEC, but that is another blog post)</em>. As I was building out the membership login/payment functionality<!-- more -->, I was able to  seriously dive into PHP for the first time. PHP is the server-side language that makes up the heart and soul of WordPress and so far it is a lot of fun to work with.</p>

<p>Anyway, Wordpress has been and continues to be a great CMS for myself and my clients, but I have recently discovered a potential game changer for how I develop Content Management Systems, if not a complete game changer then at least a worthy option. I am referring to <a href="http://statamic.com/">Statamic</a>.</p>

<p><img src="/images/statamic.png"></p>

<p>Statamic is a dynamic, static site generator.  <code>static + dynamic = Statamic</code>. Pretty clever.</p>

<p>In the words of Statamic's creator <a href="http://jackmcdade.com/">Jack McDade</a></p>

<blockquote>Statamic is a dynamic, flat file content management system that’s completely powered by static files. That’s right, there’s no database in between your application and your content.</blockquote>


<p>That sounds pretty awesome to me. Bring it.</p>

<p>There are tons of resources and documentation on the <a href="http://statamic.com/">Statamic Home Page</a> and the developer community is already robust, which means this platform should be in active development for a while and the third party add-ons should cover a variety of needs. Also, at $29 for a Personal license and $99 for a Professional license, you get a lot of bang for your buck. Without a doubt, I will be buying this for my next project.</p>

<p>Has anyone used this platform? Is anyone developing Add-Ons?</p>

<p>Please share your thoughts and experience.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Winter]]></title>
    <link href="http://middle8media.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/happy-winter/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-16T14:57:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://middle8media.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/happy-winter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A little project I did for <a href="https://vimeo.com/groups/fivebyfive">5 vignettes</a>. Enjoy and have a Happy Winter :7)</p>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/17566912 "></iframe></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
